## **NIRAJAN SANGRAULA**

neerazansangraula14@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/nirajan-sangraula | github.com/NIrajan-15

### **SUMMARY**

A Senior Undergraduate experienced in developing multi-tier, client/server applications, and web applications, and familiar with android application development. Experienced working in an **Agile/Scrum** development environment. An enthusiastic and goal-oriented team player having high-level communication, interpersonal and adaptability skills.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Louisiana Monroe(ULM) – Monroe, Louisiana

Bachelor of Science – Computer Science (Honors) with minor in Mathematics

### **EXPERIENCE**

## **DXC Technology**

Technical Intern May 2022 – Aug 2022

- Collaboratively worked in an Agile environment with a team of 48 interns for testing, design, development, and deployment of a cloud-native application for talent acquisition based on skills, and availability within the company.
- Worked as a solution architect, cloud engineer, full-stack developer, and data analyst in 4 fast-paced sprints to
  design a microservices solution architecture, design, analyzed, deploy and test business and forecast dashboards
  using **Power BI**, embed reports into a custom web application and host power BI desktop in an **ec2** instance.
- Automated data flow from the **on-premises data gateway** on a schedule to power BI, using **ODBC** data source to refresh data and update the dashboards.
- Acted as a tech lead and scrum master in one of the sprints.
- Used JIRA for user stories and GIT for version control.

### **IBM Technology Louisiana Economic Development Grant**

Software Developer

Aug 2021 – May 2022

Degree Expected: May 2023

- Actively involved in the analysis, definition, design, implementation, and deployment of full Software Development Life Cycle(SDLC) of projects.
- Designed, analyzed, developed, and tested the front-end and back-end servlets and deployed them on the AWS
  environment.
- Implemented REST API using Django and developed a SQL database model and schema in MySQL for the app's backend and Bootstrap for designing, HTML5, CSS, React, and JavaScript for developing the presentation layer.
- Agile/Scrum was used as the project management methodology.

# **University of Louisiana Monroe**

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant, Department of Computer Science

Feb 2022 – May 2022

- Assumed the role of a graduate student as a junior undergrad to aid the professor in facilitating daily 2-hour lectures on an introduction to programming Python and Java.
- Supplied guidelines and solutions for programming problems and cleared doubts on programming concepts.

### **SKILLS**

Languages: Java, Python, JavaScript. Methodology: Agile, Waterfall.

Markup Languages: HTML, XML, JSON. Front-end: Bootstrap, Figma, CSS, ReactJS.

**Back-end**: Django, NodeJS, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MySQL. **Miscellaneous**: Power BI, Git, AWS, Android Studio, VS Code.